<PAGE>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURES" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURE_CSD" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	<PARSE file="menu2-features.xml" />

	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

<h1>Cisco Secure Desktop</h1>

<p>The CSD ('Cisco Secure Desktop') mechanism is a security scanner
for the <a href="anyconnect.html">Cisco AnyConnect</a> VPNs, in the
same vein as <a href="juniper.html">Juniper's Host Checker (tncc.jar)</a>
and <a href="hip.html">GlobalProtect's HIP</a>.</p>

<h2>Background</h2>

<p>The 'Cisco Secure Desktop' is a bit of a misnomer &#8212; it works by
downloading a trojan binary from the server and running it on your
client machine to perform some kind of 'verification' and post its
approval back to the server. This seems anything <em>but</em> secure
to me, especially given their history of trivially-exploitable
bugs.</p>
<p>It's also fairly easy to subvert, by running your own modified binary
instead of the one you download from the server. Or by running their
binary but poking at it with gdb.</p>
<p>We support this idiocy, but because of the security concerns the
trojan will be executed only if a userid is specified on the command
line using the <tt>--csd-user=</tt> option, or the <tt>--csd-wrapper=</tt>
option is used to handle the script in a 'safe' manner.</p>
<p>
This support currently only works when the server has a Linux binary
installed, and only when that Linux binary runs on the client machine.</p>

<h2>CSD support in OpenConnect</h2>

<p>OpenConnect supports running the CSD binary, or spoofing its
behaviour, by passing the <tt>--csd-wrapper=SCRIPT</tt> argument
with a shell script.</p>

<p>The OpenConnect distribution includes <i>two</i> alternative
scripts to support the execution or spoofing of the CSD behaviour, in
the <tt>trojans/</tt> subdirectory:</p>

<ul>
  <li><tt>csd-wrapper.sh</tt>: This script accepts the same options as some versions of the CSD trojan binary,
  (<tt>-ticket</tt>, <tt>-stub</tt>, <tt>-group</tt>, <tt>-certhash</tt>, <tt>-url</tt>, <tt>-langselen</tt>),
  downloads the files required by the binary, and then wraps the execution of the <tt>cstub</tt> binary.
  Because of the security dangers of executing a server-provided trojan binary, this script should ideally be executed
  with the permissions of a low-privilege user (e.g. <tt>--csd-user=nobody --csd-wrapper=trojans/csd-wrapper.sh</tt>).
  </li>

  <li><tt>csd-post.sh</tt>: This script does <i>not</i> actually run the CSD trojan binary. Instead, it emulates
  the behaviour of the CSD trojan, creating a plaintext report similar to the one that the CSD trojans build, and
  uploading it to the server sent by the VPN gateway. It requires the <tt>xmlstarlet</tt> tool for parsing XML
  sent by the server, to extract a token value. The report may need to be customized in order to be accepted by some
  servers; the <a href="https://github.com/Gilks/hostscan-bypass">hostscan-bypass</a> tool may help with this.
  Because this script does not actually execute a trojan binary, and because its complete output is easily visible
  in the script, the security concerns are greatly alleviated.
  </li>
</ul>

<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>
