<PAGE>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_INDEX" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_DOWNLOAD" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	<PARSE file="menu2.xml" />
	
	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

    	<h1>Download</h1>

<p>Released versions of OpenConnect are available from the FTP site:</p>
<ul><li><a href="ftp://ftp.infradead.org/pub/openconnect/"><tt>ftp://ftp.infradead.org/pub/openconnect/</tt></a></li></ul>

<p>Release tarballs (since 3.13) are signed with the PGP key with fingerprint <a href="https://pgp.mit.edu/pks/lookup?op=vindex&amp;search=0xBE07D9FD54809AB2C4B0FF5F63762CDA67E2F359">BE07 D9FD 5480 9AB2 C4B0  FF5F 6376 2CDA 67E2 F359</a>.</p>

<p>
<!-- latest-release-start -->
The latest release is <a href="ftp://ftp.infradead.org/pub/openconnect/openconnect-8.00.tar.gz">OpenConnect v8.00</a>
<i>(<a href="ftp://ftp.infradead.org/pub/openconnect/openconnect-8.00.tar.gz.asc">PGP signature</a>)</i>,
released on 2019-01-05 with the following changelog:</p>
     <ul>
       <li>Clear form submissions (which may include passwords) before freeing (CVE-2018-20319).</li>
       <li>Allow form responses to be provided on command line.</li>
       <li>Add support for SSL keys stored in <a href="tpm.html">TPM2</a>.</li>
       <li>Fix ESP rekey when replay protection is disabled.</li>
       <li>Drop support for GnuTLS older than 3.2.10.</li>
       <li>Fix <tt>--passwd-on-stdin</tt> for Windows to not forcibly open console.</li>
       <li>Fix portability of shell scripts in test suite.</li>
       <li>Add Google Authenticator TOTP support for Juniper.</li>
       <li>Add RFC7469 key PIN support for cert hashes.</li>
       <li>Add protocol method to securely log out the Juniper session.</li>
       <li>Relax requirements for Juniper hostname packet response to support old gateways.</li>
       <li>Add API functions to query the supported protocols.</li>
       <li>Verify ESP sequence numbers and warn even if replay protection is disabled.</li>
       <li>Add support for PAN GlobalProtect VPN protocol (<tt>--protocol=gp</tt>).</li>
       <li>Reorganize listing of command-line options, and include information on supported protocols.</li>
       <li>SIGTERM cleans up the session similarly to SIGINT.</li>
     </ul>
<!-- latest-release-end -->

<p>For older releases and change logs, see the <a href="changelog.html">changelog page</a>.</p>

<p><i>(Note: Due to a longstanding <a href="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/show_bug.cgi?id=450853">Fedora bug</a>
you may occasionally find that the FTP server is accessible only by IPv6 and not Legacy IP. If this happens,
please let me know by sending me an email. Or just join us in the 21st century and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_IPv6_tunnel_brokers">get IPv6</a>.)</i></p>

<h2>Latest sources</h2>

<p>The latest source code is available from the git repository at:</p>
<ul><li><tt>git://git.infradead.org/users/dwmw2/openconnect.git</tt><br/>or browseable in gitweb at:</li>
<li><a href="http://git.infradead.org/users/dwmw2/openconnect.git">
http://git.infradead.org/users/dwmw2/openconnect.git</a></li></ul>

	<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>
