<PAGE>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURES" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURE_TNCC" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	<PARSE file="menu2-features.xml" />

	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

<h1>Juniper Host Checker (tncc.jar)</h1>

<p>The Host Checker mechanism is a security scanner for the <a
href="juniper.html">Juniper</a> VPNs, in the same vein as <a
href="csd.html">Cisco's CSD</a> and <a href="hip.html">GlobalProtect's
HIP</a>.</p>

<h3>Background</h3>

<p>Many sites require a Java applet to run certain tests as a precondition
of authentication. This works by sending a <tt>DSPREAUTH</tt> cookie
to the client which is attempting to authenticate, and the Java code
in <tt>tncc.jar</tt> then runs and communicates with the server, handing
back a new value for the <tt>DSPREAUTH</tt> cookie to be used when
autnentication continues.</p>

<p>This Java applet is a black-box binary provided by a server outside
of the client's control, and therefore has similar security concerns to Cisco's CSD
trojan.</p>

<h2>TNCC support in OpenConnect</h2>

<p>OpenConnect supports running the tncc.jar binary with a little assistance. A Python wrapper
script, <tt>tncc-wrapper.py</tt>, is provided in the <tt>trojans/</tt> subdirectory of the
OpenConnect distribution. It can be used
along with the <tt>tncc-preload.so</tt> from
<a href="https://github.com/russdill/ncsvc-socks-wrapper">this repository</a>.
It may also be necessary to pass a Mozilla-compatible user agent string:
<pre>
  ./openconnect --protocol=nc --useragent 'Mozilla/5.0 (Linux) Firefox' --csd-wrapper=trojans/tncc-wrapper.py vpn.example.com
</pre>
Because of the security dangers of executing a server-provided trojan binary, this script should ideally be executed
with the permissions of a low-privilege user (e.g. <tt>--csd-user=nobody</tt>).
</p>

<p>Alternatively, the <a href="https://github.com/russdill/juniper-vpn-py">juniper-vpn-py</a> project provides a
<tt>tncc.py</tt> which <i>emulates</i> the behaviour of the <tt>tncc.jar</tt> binary, rather than actually
executing it. Because this script does not actually execute a server-provided binary, security concerns are greatly
alleviated. However, this alternative script may require customization to work with VPNs that have modified
the behaviour of their Host Checker binaries in some way.
</p>


<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>
