<PAGE>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURES" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURE_TPM" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	<PARSE file="menu2-features.xml" />

	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

<h1>Trusted Platform Module (TPM) support</h1>

<p>OpenConnect supports the use of private keys secured or "wrapped"
by a TPM. Instead of being stored inside the trusted hardware as with
typical PKCS#11 keys, the key is encrypted by the TPM and handed back
to the user to be saved in a PEM file. Only the same TPM can decrypt
the file, and use the private key.</p>

<p>Use of TPM-wrapped keys is intended to be entirely
transparent. OpenConnect will automatically use the TPM when presented
with an appropriate PEM file with a TPM-wrapped key.</p>

<p>When OpenConnect is built with OpenSSL, the appropriate TPM ENGINE
must be installed correctly on the system, and OpenConnect will load
and use it automatically when appropriate.
</p>
<p>For GnuTLS builds of OpenConnect, it needs to have been built with
the appropriate TPM (v1 or v2) support built-in.</p>

<h2>TPM v1</h2>

<p>TPM v1 wrapped keys appear in the form of a PEM file marked with the tag:
<pre>-----BEGIN TSS KEY BLOB-----</pre>
These files can be created by the <tt>create_tpm_key</tt> tool which is
part of the
<a href="https://github.com/mgerstner/openssl_tpm_engine">OpenSSL
TPM ENGINE</a> or the <a href="https://www.gnutls.org/manual/html_node/tpmtool-Invocation.html">tpmtool</a> which is part of the GnuTLS distribution.</p>

<h2>TPM v2</h2>

<p>As from the 8.0 release, OpenConnect supports TPM v2 wrapped keys.
These have the PEM tag:
<pre>-----BEGIN TSS2 PRIVATE KEY-----</pre>

There are two ENGINE implementations for TPM v2 with OpenSSL,
based on different TSS libraries.</p>

<p><a href="https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/jejb/openssl_tpm2_engine.git/"><tt>openssl_tpm2_engine</tt></a> is based on <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/ibmtpm20tss/">IBM's TPM 2.0 TSS</a>, while
<a href="https://github.com/tpm2-software/tpm2-tss-engine"><tt>tpm2-tss-engine</tt></a> uses the
<a href="https://github.com/tpm2-software/tpm2-tss">Intel/TCG stack</a>. OpenConnect can use
either ENGINE.</p>


<p>The GnuTLS build of OpenConnect can use either TSS library.</p>

<p>Older keys from <tt>openssl_tpm2_engine</tt> may have the tag:
<pre>-----BEGIN TSS2 KEY BLOB-----</pre></p>

This format is also supported by the GnuTLS builds of OpenConnect.

<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>
